<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
    <name>Minimum Spanning Tree Clustering</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Uses Prim’s algorithm to build a minimum spanning tree for each cluster, stopping when the nearest- * nneighbour distance rises above a specified threshold. Returns a set of clusters and a set of ’outliers’ not in any cluster.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Uses Prim’s algorithm to build a minimum spanning tree for each cluster, stopping when the nearest- * nneighbour distance rises above a specified threshold. Returns a set of clusters and a set of ’outliers’ not in any cluster.
        <br/>
		<br/>
		More details about package "nnclust" and "Minimum spanning tree clustering"("nnclust"):
		<br/>
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/nnclust/nnclust.pdf">nnclust</a> 
        <br/>
        <br/>
		More details about R:
		<br/>
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a>
		<br/>
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
        
        
        <tab name="Standard Options">
        	<option name="Filter">Filtering of data matrix or data frame. Each row must correspond to an observation, and each column must correspond to a variable. All variables must be numeric. Missing values (NAs) are allowed.</option>
        	<option name="Threshold">Threshold for stopping the tree building within a cluster. The tree stops when the squared euclidean distance to the closest point to the tree is greater than this.</option>
        </tab>
        
        <tab name="Advanced Options">
        	<option name="Fill">Stop when the clusters make up this fraction of the data.</option>
        	<option name="Maximum number of clusters">Stop at this many clusters.</option>
        	<option name="Give up">Stop when fewer than this many pairs have nearest-neighbor distance less than threshold.</option>
        	<option name="Start">Integer index to start the minimum spanning tree at this observation.</option>
        	<option name="Outlier">If FALSE, use NA for the cluster identifier for outliers.</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data input">Data input</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data output">R MAD Result Data</outPort>
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="R MAD Std Output">The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.</view>
        <view index="1" name="R MAD Err Output">The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
