<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
    <name>MovMF</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Fit mixtures of von Mises-Fisher Distributions.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Fit mixtures of von Mises-Fisher Distributions.
        <br/>
		<br/>
		More details about "movMF":
		<br/>
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/movMF/movMF.pdf">movMF</a> 
        <br/>
        <br/>
		More details about R:
		<br/>
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a>
		<br/>
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
        
        
        <tab name="Standard Options">
        	<option name="Filter">Filtering of data matrix or data frame. Each row must correspond to an observation, and each column must correspond to a variable. All variables must be numeric. Missing values (NAs) are allowed.</option>
        	<option name="Clusters">The number of clusters. It is required that 0 &lt; clusters &lt; n where n is the number of observations</option>
        </tab>
        
        <tab name="Advanced Options">
        	<option name="Max. iter">An integer giving the maximal number of EM iterations to be performed. Default: 100.</option>
        	<option name="reltol">The minimum relative improvement of the objective function per iteration. If improvement is less, the EM algorithm will stop under the assumption that no further significant improvement can be made. Default value will be set depending on the numerical characteristics of the machine R is running on (sqrt(.Machine$double.eps)).</option>
        	<option name="Start">A specification of the starting values to be employed. Can be a character vector with elements "i" (randomly pick component ids for the observations), or one of "p", "S" or "s". The latter first determine component “prototypes”, and then determine an optimal “fuzzy” membership matrix from the implied cosine dissimilarities between observations and prototypes. Prototypes are obtained as follows: for "p", observations are randomly picked. For "S", one takes the first prototype to minimize total cosine dissimilarity to the observations, and then successively picks observations farthest away from the already picked prototypes. For "s", one takes a randomly chosen observation as the first prototype, and then proceeds as for "S". By default, initialization method "p" is used. If several starting values are specified, the EM algorithm is performed individually to each starting value, and the best solution found is returned.</option>
        	<option name="nruns">An integer giving the number of EM runs to be performed. Default: 1. Only used if start is not given.</option>
        	<option name="Min. alpha">A numeric indicating the minimum prior probability. Components falling below this threshold are removed during the iteration. If &gt;= 1, this is taken as the minimal number of observations in a component. Default: 0.</option>
        	<option name="Converge">Logical, if TRUE the EM algorithm is stopped if the reltol criterion is met and the current parameter estimate is returned. If FALSE the EM algorithm is run for maxiter iterations and the parametrizations with the maximum likelihood encountered during the EM algorithm is returned. Default: TRUE, changed to FALSE if E="stochmax".</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data input">Data input</inPort>

        <outPort index="0" name="Data output">R MAD Result Data</outPort>

    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="R MAD Std Output">The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.</view>
        <view index="1" name="R MAD Err Output">The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>