<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
    <name>Parallel Model-Based Clustering</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Parallel Model-Based Clustering.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        The pmclust aims to utilize model-based clustering (unsupervised) for high dimensional and ultra large data, especially in a distributed manner. The package employs pbdMPI to perform a parallel version of expectation and maximization (EM) algorithm for finite mixture Gaussian models. The unstructured dispersion matrices are assumed in the Gaussian models. The implementation is default in the single program multiple data (SPMD) programming model. The code can be executed through pbdMPI and independent to most MPI applications. See the High Performance Statistical Computing (HPSC) website for more information, documents and examples.
        <br/>
		<br/>
		More details about "pmclust":
		<br/>
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/pmclust/pmclust.pdf">pmclust</a> 
        <br/>
        <br/>
		More details about R:
		<br/>
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a>
		<br/>
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
        
        
         <tab name="Standard Options">
        	<option name="Filter">Filtering of data matrix or data frame. Each row must correspond to an observation, and each column must correspond to a variable. All variables must be numeric. Missing values (NAs) are allowed.</option>
        	<option name="Clusters">The number of clusters. It is required that 0 &lt; clusters &lt; n where n is the number of observations</option>
        </tab>
        
        <tab name="Advanced Options">
            <option name="Algorithm">Types of EM algorithms.</option>
            <option name="RndEM.iter">number of Rand-EM iterations.</option>
            <option name="Method own X">How X is distributed.</option>
            <option name="Rank own X">Who own X if method.own.X = "single".</option>
        </tab>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data input">Data input</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data output">R MAD Result Data</outPort>
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="R MAD Std Output">The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.</view>
        <view index="1" name="R MAD Err Output">The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>