<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Clara</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Computes a "clara" object, a list representing a clustering of the data into k clusters. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Computes a "clara" object, a list representing a clustering of the data into k clusters.
        <br/>
		<br/>
		More details about package "cluster" and "clara":
		<br/>
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/cluster/cluster.pdf">cluster</a> 
        <br/>
        <br/>
		More details about R:
		<br/>
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a>
		<br/>
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
        
        <tab name="Standard Options">
        	<option name="Filter">Filtering of data matrix or data frame. Each row must correspond to an observation, and each column must correspond to a variable. All variables must be numeric. Missing values (NAs) are allowed.</option>
        	<option name="Clusters">The number of clusters. It is required that 0 &lt; clusters &lt; n where n is the number of observations</option>
        </tab>
        
        <tab name="Advanced Options">
        	<option name="Metric">Character string specifying the metric to be used for calculating dissimilarities between observations. The currently available options are "euclidean" and "manhattan". Euclidean distances are root sum-of-squares of differences, and manhattan distances are the sum of absolute differences. </option>
        	<option name="Stand">Indicates if the measurements are standardized before calculating the dissimilarities. Measurements are standardized for each variable (column), by subtracting the variable's mean value and dividing by the variable's mean absolute deviation. </option>
        	<option name="Samples">Indicates the number of samples to be drawn from the dataset. The default, 5, is rather small for historical (and now back compatibility) reasons and we recommend to set samples an order of magnitude larger. </option>
        	<option name="Sampsize">The number of observations in each sample. Sampsize should be higher than the number of clusters (k) and at most the number of observations.</option>
        	<option name="Trace">Indicates a trace level for diagnostic output during the algorithm.</option>
        	<option name="Medoids.x">Indicates if the medoids should be returned, identically to some rows of the input data x. If FALSE, keep.data will be set to false as well, and the medoid indices, i.e., row numbers of the medoids will still be returned, and the algorithm saves space by needing one copy less of x.</option>
        	<option name="Keep data">Indicates if the (scaled if 'stand' is true) data should be kept in the result. Setting this to FALSE saves memory (and hence time). Use medoids.x = FALSE to save even more memory.</option>
        	<option name="rngR">Indicates if R's random number generator should be used instead of the primitive clara()-builtin one. If true, this also means that each call to clara() returns a different result – though only slightly different in good situations.</option>
        	<option name="pamLike">Indicates if the “swap” phase should use the same algorithm as pam(). Note that from Kaufman and Rousseeuw's description this should have been true always, but as the original Fortran code and the subsequent port to C has always contained a small one-letter change (a typo according to Martin Maechler) with respect to PAM, the default, pamLike = FALSE has been chosen to remain back compatible rather than “PAM compatible”.</option>
        </tab>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data input">Data input</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data output">R MAD Result Data</outPort>
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="R MAD Std Output">The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.</view>
        <view index="1" name="R MAD Err Output">The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
